<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>iscsi on Blah, Cloud</title>
    <link>https://blah.cloud/tags/iscsi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iscsi on Blah, Cloud</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://blah.cloud/images/logo-title.png</url>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/images/logo-title.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 12:59:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blah.cloud/tags/iscsi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Replicating SAN on openSUSE with VAAI</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/hardware/replicating-san-opensuse-vaai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 12:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/hardware/replicating-san-opensuse-vaai/</guid>
      <description>Preamble This article was written a few years back, but never published - it was some work I was doing in my lab to try and get to grips around the work involved in creating a SAN with synchronous replication built in from scratch.
It in no way should be used for production, but rather as a learning exercise - as previously stated the instructions are a few years old and version specific, so openSUSE may well now support some of the modules I had to compile and create repos for manually, also DRBD9 has been released and should obviously be used in place of DRBD8 as I have below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Multi-NIC vMotion in vSphere 5.5</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/hardware/setting-multi-nic-vmotion-vsphere-5-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 15:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/hardware/setting-multi-nic-vmotion-vsphere-5-5/</guid>
      <description>Multi-NIC vMotion is a no-brainer configuration for performance:
 Faster maintenance mode operations Better DRS load balance operations Overall reduction in lead time of a manual vMotion process.  It was introduced in vSphere 5.0 and has improved in v5.5 - so let&amp;rsquo;s get into how to configure it (we&amp;rsquo;ll be using the vSphere Web Client because that&amp;rsquo;s what VMWare wants us to do nowadays&amp;hellip;).
 I don&amp;rsquo;t have an Enterprise Plus license so no Distributed Switches for me - however, if you do have Distributed Switching licenses you should be able to extrapolate from my Standard Switching how to config yours</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
