<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>vsphere on Blah, Cloud</title>
    <link>https://blah.cloud/tag/vsphere/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vsphere on Blah, Cloud</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://blah.cloud/images/logo-text.png</url>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/images/logo-text.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 12:21:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blah.cloud/tag/vsphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ClusterAPI for vSphere, now with CNS support</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/clusterapi-for-vsphere-now-with-cns-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 12:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/clusterapi-for-vsphere-now-with-cns-support/</guid>
      <description>Using CAPV to deploy K8s clusters with vSphere CNS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Velero for K8s Backup and Restore of CSI Volumes</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/automation/using-velero-for-k8s-backup-and-restore-of-csi-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 12:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/automation/using-velero-for-k8s-backup-and-restore-of-csi-volumes/</guid>
      <description>How to backup and restore K8s applications on vSphere</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First-look: Automated K8s lifecycle with ClusterAPI</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/first-look-automated-k8s-lifecycle-with-clusterapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 14:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/first-look-automated-k8s-lifecycle-with-clusterapi/</guid>
      <description>Using CAPV alpha to spin up K8s clusters on vSphere</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using cloud-init for VM templating on vSphere</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/using-cloud-init-for-vm-templating-on-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 19:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/using-cloud-init-for-vm-templating-on-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>Step by step guide for using cloud-init on vSphere</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the vSphere Cloud Provider for K8s to dynamically deploy volumes</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/using-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-for-k8s-to-dynamically-deploy-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 22:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/using-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-for-k8s-to-dynamically-deploy-volumes/</guid>
      <description>How to provision Kubernetes Persistent Volumes dynamically on vSphere</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up K8s and the vSphere Cloud Provider using kubeadm</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/setting-up-k8s-and-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-using-kubeadm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/setting-up-k8s-and-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-using-kubeadm/</guid>
      <description>How to enable the vSphere Cloud Provider with kubeadm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an Ubuntu 18.04 LTS cloud image for cloning on VMware</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/creating-an-ubuntu-18-04-lts-cloud-image-for-cloning-on-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 23:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/kubernetes/creating-an-ubuntu-18-04-lts-cloud-image-for-cloning-on-vmware/</guid>
      <description>Intro I have been experimenting a lot over the past 18 months with containers and in particular, Kubernetes, and one of the core things I always seemed to get hung up on was part-zero - creating the VMs to actually run K8s. I wanted a CLI only way to build a VM template for the OS and then deploy that to the cluster.
It turns out that with Ubuntu 18.04 LTS (in particular the cloud image OVA) there are a few things need changed from the base install (namely cloud-init) in order to make them play nice with OS Guest Customisation in vCenter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating vSAN vmkernel ports to a new subnet</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/migrating-vsan-vmkernel-ports-new-subnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 14:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/migrating-vsan-vmkernel-ports-new-subnet/</guid>
      <description>After deploying a vSAN cluster, the need sometimes arises to make changes to its network configuration, such as migrating the vmkernel network of the cluster to a new subnet. This requirement may appear for example when changing the network in which the vSAN cluster is running, or even, in a more complex scenario such as when a standalone vSAN needs to be converted to a stretched cluster.
In these sorts of situations, complications may be encountered if the subnet in use for the vSAN vmkernel ports cannot be routed to the network as a whole, as it is in use elsewhere in the organization, and is currently isolated in an L2 segment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 Host Resources Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/hardware/vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 12:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/hardware/vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 6-9 months, I have been reviewing the vast majority of a new book just released to print by Frank Denneman and Niels Hagoort - The vSphere 6.5 Host Resources Deep Dive.
 
This book is, without a doubt, the most in-depth look at host design I have ever read, we are not talking about standard best practices here, though those are in there too. More, low-level understanding of why best practices exist and even challenging some existing perceptions and paradigms about why technologies should be used and more importantly, how they should be utilised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Auto Deploy Stateless Caching in vSphere 6.0</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/automation/configuring-auto-deploy-stateless-caching-vsphere-6-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 21:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/automation/configuring-auto-deploy-stateless-caching-vsphere-6-0/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my previous post on configuring custom ESXi images for PXE deployment, it piqued my interest again in Auto Deploy, now that I have a lab large enough (enough physical failure domains) to justify auto-deploy I figured i&amp;rsquo;d give it another go. I have chosen to implement stateless caching as it will allow the hosts to boot from the last used ESXi image they had if the PxE/AutoDeploy server goes down - then when it comes back up will pull the new version, this accounts for a total infrastructure outage and still allows the hosts to be bootable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Update Manager – Cannot Scan Host</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/virtualisation/vsphere-update-manager-cannot-scan-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 14:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/virtualisation/vsphere-update-manager-cannot-scan-host/</guid>
      <description>I have been testing out Runecast Analyzer in my lab recently - it&amp;rsquo;s pretty badass, you can set it up to scan your virtual infrastructure at a vCenter level and will scan your vC, VMs and hosts looking for KBs that may apply, security compliance and best practises.
 
As you can see my lab isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a model config when it comes to any of these things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSAN Observer RVC in vCenter Appliance 6.0 U1</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/virtualisation/vsan-observer-rvc-in-vcenter-appliance-6-0-u1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 09:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/virtualisation/vsan-observer-rvc-in-vcenter-appliance-6-0-u1/</guid>
      <description>Using vSAN observer inside vCenter 6.0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safely check/remove orphaned VMDK files from ESXi</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/safely-checkremove-orphaned-vmdk-files-from-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 13:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/safely-checkremove-orphaned-vmdk-files-from-esxi/</guid>
      <description>How to check if VMDKs are actively being used by a VM, and how to safely remove them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Multi-NIC vMotion in vSphere 5.5</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/hardware/setting-multi-nic-vmotion-vsphere-5-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 15:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/hardware/setting-multi-nic-vmotion-vsphere-5-5/</guid>
      <description>Multi-NIC vMotion is a no-brainer configuration for performance:
 Faster maintenance mode operations Better DRS load balance operations Overall reduction in lead time of a manual vMotion process.  It was introduced in vSphere 5.0 and has improved in v5.5 - so let&amp;rsquo;s get into how to configure it (we&amp;rsquo;ll be using the vSphere Web Client because that&amp;rsquo;s what VMWare wants us to do nowadays&amp;hellip;).
 I don&amp;rsquo;t have an Enterprise Plus license so no Distributed Switches for me - however, if you do have Distributed Switching licenses you should be able to extrapolate from my Standard Switching how to config yours</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading vCenter Server Appliance to vCSA 5.5</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/upgrading-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 23:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/upgrading-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5/</guid>
      <description>How to upgrade your vCenter Server Appliance to 5.5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Hot-Add Mode Fails – Mismatching VMFS block size</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/veeam-hot-add-mode-fails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 11:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/veeam-hot-add-mode-fails/</guid>
      <description>Solution for VMDK hot-add mode failing when using Veeam Backup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero free space using SDelete to shrink Thin Provisioned VMDK</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/zero-free-space-using-sdelete-shrink-thin-provisioned-vmdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 08:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/infrastructure/zero-free-space-using-sdelete-shrink-thin-provisioned-vmdk/</guid>
      <description>Guide to show how to reclaim disk space by zeroing out free space on thin provisioned VMDKs using sdelete</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extend Dell MD3000i Virtual Disk LUN Size</title>
      <link>https://blah.cloud/hardware/extend-dell-md3000i-virtual-disk-lun-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 12:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blah.cloud/hardware/extend-dell-md3000i-virtual-disk-lun-size/</guid>
      <description>Showing how to extending a LUN backed by a Dell MD3000i SAN&amp;#39;s Virtual Disk</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
